Guide to the George and Katy Abraham Papers, 1915-2005
Abraham, George and Katy papers.
- Series II. Gardening
  - Clippings, correspondence, photos and slides, Green Thumb articles, and personal files
    - Correspondence with various publishers, 1990's (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Green Thumb Tips for your Golden Years" manuscript (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Misc. Green Thumb columns, 1970-2004 (Box 14, Folder 16-20)
    - "Houseplants" book cancellation letter from Macmillan Publishing (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Book reviews and misc. clippings (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Book reviews (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Old Farmer's Almanac correspondence and submissions, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Indoor Houseplants" manuscript, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Elder workshops (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Green Thumb tips for your golden years (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Myths and Facts by Doc and Katy (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Green Thumb Radio show bulletins (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - Manuscript of non-fiction stories by Doc in Africa, sent to NY Times 194- (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Original manuscript for Green Thumb Garden Handbook, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    - Blank Green Thumb stationery (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Misc. 2x2 slides (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Misc. photos (Box 15, Folder 17-22)
    - Photo album (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Misc. news clippings and correspondence (Box 15, Folder 24-25)
    - Book reviews (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Green Thumb Columns (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
    - Articles about the Abrahams and their collection (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Primers for gardening pleasure" by Doc and Katy, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Organic Gardening Under Glass" by Doc and Katy Abraham (uncorrected proof) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Organic Gardening and Farming" magazine, September 1974 (Doc and Katy on cover) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "The Green Thumb Garden Handbook" by George Abraham (Annotated) (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
    - "The Belles of Shangri-La" by George Abraham (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Houseplant: How to Keep them Alive and Well" (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "How to Build and Use Greenhouses" (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - "Green Thumb Activities for Classroom Gardeners" by Doc and Katy (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "A Bathtub Built for Two" by Doc and Katy (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "The Green Thumb Book of Vegetable Gardening" by George Abraham (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "The Green Thumb Book of Fruit and Vegetable Gardening" by George Abraham, 1970 (Annotated) (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - "The Green Thumb Book of Indoor Gardening" by George Abraham, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "The Green Thumb Garden Handbook" by George Abraham, 1961 (Annotated) (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbooks of Newspaper Clippings (Columns by Doc and related articles) (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Green Thumb subject files, alphabetical
    - Aloe (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Alternatives to hazardous household products (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Animal control (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Ants (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Apples (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Artichokes (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - ASTA Garden Writers (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Beans (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Bedding plants (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Beets (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Beneficials (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Bible plants (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Biblical herbs (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Biological control (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Bird control (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Birds (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Black Leaf 40 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bonsai (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - Bromeliads (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Bugs (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Bulbs (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Butterfly gardening (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Cabbage (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Canning and freezing (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Carrots (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Cluster flies (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Community College of the Finger Lakes (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Cherries (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Chestnuts (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Chile Peppers (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Christmas trees (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Coal gardens (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Companion planting (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Compost tea (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Consumer research (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Corn (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Countryside books (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Crab apple trees (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Cucumbers (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Cut flower care (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Dandelions (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Deer repellents (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Dormant sprays (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Dried arrangements (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Dynamic Years Magazine (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Eden Ranch (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Edible Flowers (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Editor and Publisher (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Evergreens (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Flower Arranging (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Firewood (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Flowers in hospital (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Frogs (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Garlic (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Gardening factoids (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Grasses (ornamental) (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Hollies (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Horseradish (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Hydroponic gardening (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Language of flowers (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Latin book (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Latin plant names (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Lettuce (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Lights for plants (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Luffa guords (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Medicinal plants (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Melons (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Men's gardening association (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Microwaved dried flowers (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Moles (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mother Earth News (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Mulch (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - National Garden Bureau (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Nectarines (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Northeast Testers, Organic Gardening (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Nursery Business (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Nuts (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Olives (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Onions (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Organic Gardening (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Parsley (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Peas (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Pears (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Peppers (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Perovskia (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Perennial Gardens (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Perennials (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Plants Alive (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Plants Responses to Stimuli (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Plastic bag re-use in gardens (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Plums (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Poisonous plants (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Pollution effects (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Pomander balls (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Pools and pumps (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Potatoes (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Pruning fruit trees (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Pumpkins (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Quill and Trowel, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Quince (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Rhubarb (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Roses (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Shrubs (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Snails (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Soil Sterilization (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Sprayers (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Sprouts (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Squash (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Strawberries (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Storage and drying (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Sunflowers (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Systemic pesticides (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Tomatoes (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Toxic mulch (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Under glass (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Vegetables (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Venus fly traps (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Vines (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Water (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Water witching (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Watering and irrigation (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Weed killers and chemical sprays (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Wild rice (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - WOKR-TV (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - WOKR-TV Segment topics (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Personal, Green Thumb, and gardening videotapes
    - Best Friends: Doc & Katy Abraham: V-888 (Box 20)
    - Robbi Hawkin: V-889 (Box 20)
    - At Home Magazine, 3/28/93: V-890 (Box 20)
    - At Home Magazine, 7/04/93: V-891 (Box 20)
    - Iris farm perennials, 1979: V-892 (Box 20)
    - Green Thumb: Bob Mann's garden: V-893 (Box 20)
    - Christmas Decorations with Ron Guidone: V-894 (Box 20)
    - Glen Iris, Bob Mann, robins 5/4/96: V-895 (Box 20)
    - Doc & Katey Abraham: 1st grades, 4/12/96: V-896 (Box 20)
    - Barbara Lyons Plant Gift Ideas Good: V-897 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Home of Chuck Hallack: V-898 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Blueberries: V-899 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Pruning: V-900 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Protect Trees and Nuts: V-901 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Cumming's Nature Center: V-902 (Box 19)
    - NCS Elementary School: V-903 (Box 19)
    - A.M.R. Fridays - Doc and Katy: V-904 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Iris and Poison Ivy Watering Plants: V-905 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Fall Bouquet: V-906 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Blue Birds: V-907 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Sam Loyawcano: V-908 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb: V-909 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Mushrooms: V-910 (Box 19)
    - Green Thumb - Mulches: V-911 (Box 19)
  - Green Thumb and gardening CDs
    - WHAM - Doc & Katy, 1/28/05: CD-330 (Box 20)
    - Selections of images from Doc Abraham 2: CD-331 (Box 20)
    - Doc & Katy's book about funny incidents: CD-332 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb program: CD-333 (Box 20)
    - Selections of images from Doc Abraham 1: CD-334 (Box 20)
  - Green Thumb and gardening DVDs
    - A Tribute to Doc & Katy: DVD-210 (Box 20)
  - Audio tapes
    - Harold Dubois, 80090: tr8174 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb, Sat., June 30th: tr8175 (Box 20)
    - C. Brink tape, WHAM, 1955-56: tr8176 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb, 10/4/75: tr8177 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb, Christmas Day, Saturday 12/15: tr8178 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb (Sunday), 6-23-79: tr8179 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb (Saturday) 6/16/79: tr8180 (Box 20)
    - Green Thumb, 7/7/79: tr8181 (Box 20)
    - The Green Thumb (Sunday), 6/9/79: tr8182 (Box 20)
    - Doc & Katy at Naples Rotary: tr8239a (Box 20)
  - Negatives: non-African
    - George Junior Republic (Box 4, Folder 103-113)
  - Oversize and miscellaneous personal materials
    - Sheet music: "K-K-K-Katy" (Box 21)
    - American Iris Society certificate of entry in the Iris Register of "Doc and Katy" iris (Box 21)
    - Ticket for "eye openers": Spring Gardening by Doc and Katy Abraham at McCurdy's Midtown (Box 21)
    - Invitation to "Victory on the Verandah," Ontario County Historical Society, Canandaigua, NY (Box 21)
    - Photograph of a steeple (Box 21)
    - Aerial photograph of a nursery with greenhouses (Box 21)
    - Math Matters: p. 29 (Box 21)
    - Certificate of Recognition for Outstanding Service from Willard Psychiatric Center Volunteer Program, Office of Mental Health (Box 21)
    - Meet the OG Organic Gardening) Regional Testers (Box 21)
    - Editor & Publisher sheet, 1978 recognizing 30 years of garden writing in the Green Thumb (Box 21)
    - Green Thumb column, and award notice for Men's Garden Club of America (Box 21)
    - Katherine Mehlenbacher Abraham diploma from Cornell University, 1969 (Box 21)
    - American Horticultural Society citation of George and Katy Abraham (Box 21)
    - Award of Merit to George & Katy Abraham by the Garden Writers Association of America: 1988 Quill & Trowel Communication Award (Box 21)
    - Certificate of Recognition of Katherine Abraham by Seven Lakes Girl Scout Council, Inc.; Phelps, NY; 1996 (Box 21)
    - George Abraham certificate of election to Pi Alpha Xi in recognition of scholarship and achievement in Floriculture, 1938 (Box 21)
    - envelope of personal cards, miscellany (Box 21)
    - Doc and Katy Day at the Naples Elementary School (Box 21)
    - A Bathtub Built for Two (2 copies) (Box 21)
    - Clippings and reprints (Box 22)
    - Belles of Shangri-La poster (Box 22)
    - 50th anniversary card (Box 22)
    - Thank you booklets from school children (Box 22)
    - The Belles of Shangri-La (2 copies) (Box 22)